Kenta Kudo

London, United Kingdom yd37574@gmail.com +447397322375

Professional Summary

Engineering graduate with 5+ years of Software Engineering experience. I love problem solving, and transforming complicated issues into simple solutions. I am a logical thinker, diligent, curious, and collaborative. I am increasingly interested in frontend technology and its impact.

Work Experience

Utility Warehouse (London, United Kingdom) — *Software Engineer*

April 2019 ~ Present

As a member of the payment platform team, rewriting the legacy system to the new system which is scalable and maintainable with a user-friendly interface using the latest tech stack such as microservices in Go and Kubernetes is my main focus. Making the system regulation compliant is also our responsibility.

Mercari UK (London, United Kingdom) — *Junior Backend Engineer*

December 2016 ~ March 2019

My main responsibility was to add features and functions to the large user-base applications communicating with PMs to make a consumer facing app that grows in the area. I made myself an expert of a PHP and Go developer using GCP platform with OOP and TDD practices.

Smart Tech Ventures (Tokyo, Japan) — iOS Engineer

May 2015 ~ March 2017

I developed the e-commerce app using MVC architecture in Swift and Objective-C. I also wrote and created from scratch a healthcare application introducing MVVM architecture and Reactive Programming.

Education

The University of Tokyo (Tokyo, Japan) — Bachelor of Engineering

April 2011~ March 2015

Aeronautical and Astronautical Engineering

Interests

I embrace a simple lifestyle. Learning and experiencing new things are great fun for me. Besides input from tech topics, I get inspiration from books, movies, music, exercise, food, and travel.

Skills

Languages

Go – Advanced level PHP – Advanced level Swift – Advanced level Python – Intermediate level JavaScript – Intermediate level

Tools

Docker, Kubernetes, Terraform, GCP, Apache Kafka, MySQL

Practices

Object-Oriented Programming, Test-Driven Development, Event-Driven Architecture, microservices, Design Pattern

Others

Machine Learning, System Programming

Links

https://kentakudo.com

